Josh Dixon

(236) 889-6605 | Vancouver, BC

<u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>joshdixn@icloud.com</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

OBJECTIVE STATEMENT

A full stack software developer with almost 2 years of experience working in an agile environment developing, testing and peer reviewing code that reaches hundreds of thousands of users. Experienced in various test automation frameworks, JavaScript, React, NextJs, SQL and PHP and more.

WORK EXPERIENCE

The Collecting Group Ltd Website Developer

Nottingham, UK

September 2021 - April 2023

Designed, developed, tested and maintained features for two online auction websites (<u>collectingcars.com</u> and <u>watchcollecting.com</u>).

- Improved interactivity for both websites navigation to optimize user experience and tested to 100% code coverage using unit tests.
- Developed automated test suites to fully test 16+ custom web pages using Cypress.
- Raised tickets on project management software such as Jira and Asana for documenting and tracking bugs and defects.
- Migrated from AWS CodePipeline to GitHub and maintained continuous integration through CircleCI.
- Redesigned the user interface of language options and tripled the selection of language translations available through integrating and testing a third-party API.
- Saved developer time by streamlining deployment processes for website updates by implementing Contentful CMS.
- Developed microservice for handling user data and displaying badges alongside usernames. Improving trust between reputable buyers and sellers on our platform.
- Conducted an SEO audit and improved page load time and Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) score, resulting in better search engine visibility and user experience.

Nottingham Forest FC Ltd

Nottingham, UK

Team Photographer

September 2021 - April 2023

- Shot, edited and captioned imagery of matchday events, game action and press conferences.
- Oversaw the organization and maintenance of the club's image archive.
- Provided imagery for corporate partners and sponsors, including imagery of advertising materials, shirt sponsors and stadium branding.
- Produced all content in line with the club's digital strategy, brand and style.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, NextJs, Jest, Cypress, JQuery, XSLT, ChakraUI, Framer Motion, SOL

Tools: Git, GitHub, CircleCl, PHPStorm, Visual Studio Code, Figma, Contentful, Postman, Hotjar

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials | Amazon Web Services Training **UX and Accessible Design** | UAL Creative Computing Institute

EDUCATION

Worksop College
A Levels in Applied Business, Design & Technology and Physical Education
The Grove Secondary School
6 GCSE's grade A-C including Mathematics and English

Balderton, UK 2006 - 2011

Worksop, UK

2011 - 2013